Painstakingly prepared. Brilliantly executed.
The Menu is a comedy, horror, thriller film directed by Mark Mylod.
A young couple travels to a remote island to eat at an exclusive restaurant where
the chef has prepared a lavish menu, with some shocking surprises.
Margot, played by Anya Taylor-Joy.
Chef Slowik, played by Ralph Fiennes.
Tyler, played by Nicholas Hoult.
Lillian, played by Janet McTeer.
Ted, played by Paul Adelstein.
Bryce, played by Rob Yang.
The Menu is a 2022 American black comedy horror film directed by
Mark Mylod and written by Seth Reiss and Will Tracy.
It stars an ensemble cast consisting of Ralph Fiennes, Anya Taylor-Joy, Nicholas
Hoult, Hong Chau, Janet McTeer, Judith Light, and John Leguizamo.
It follows a foodie and his date travelling to a remote island to eat at an exclusive restaurant where
the chef has prepared a lavish menu but reveals shocking surprises throughout the meal.
The film had its world premiere at the 47th Toronto International Film Festival on September 10, 2022, and
was theatrically released in the United States on November 18, 2022, by Searchlight Pictures.
It grossed $79.6 million worldwide and received positive reviews from critics.
At the 80th Golden Globe Awards, Fiennes and Taylor-Joy were nominated for
Best Actor and Best Actress – Musical or Comedy, respectively.
The film earned five nominations, including Best
Thriller Film, at the 51st Saturn Awards.
The film explores themes of psychopath, obsession,
mass murder, restaurant, dark comedy.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and intense.